<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on Kwon.nyc</title>
    <link>https://kwon.nyc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on Kwon.nyc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 08:46:45 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kwon.nyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Art</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/intelligent-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 10:33:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/intelligent-art/</guid>
      <description>I signed up as a beta user for an AI art generator that uses keywords (text) to create images. The first image I asked it to make was one using the keywords korean queer mermaid liminal space and these are the four options it generated:
 Four queer Korean mermaids, drawn by a machine (generated by Midjourney)
  It&amp;rsquo;s pretty amazing that a computer made these images, and that is obviously a marvel and an incredible feat of technology, although if you look closely you can see where it still needs a little bit of work (for example, in the bottom right panel the face is fairly well done, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what&amp;rsquo;s happening with the body or why the tail is detached, and the bottom left very much seems like the generator phoned it in).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooperate</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/cooperate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 09:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/cooperate/</guid>
      <description>We joined the food co-op. I worked my first shift the other night (after work work). You choose from available shifts and sign up for the kind of work you might want to do. I chose cleaning. I had been somewhat apprehensive about working the shift, not because it was work, or even that it was work I wasn&amp;rsquo;t willing to do or anything, but moreso that it was a New Thing to do and it had been a while since I had done a New Thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:20:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/coffee/</guid>
      <description>Coffee is so good.
In addition to being physiologically and emotionally dependent on caffeine, I genuinely enjoy coffee. I have accumulated too many coffeemaking implements over the years, including but not limited to a French press, burr grinder, espresso machine, pourover cone, cold brew system, and probably others I&amp;rsquo;m forgetting that I use less frequently and are collecting dust in a cabinet. I started drinking coffee in college, mainly out of curiosity—I had a friend who said they couldn&amp;rsquo;t function without coffee, though I perceived them as a very functional person, and I thought, &amp;ldquo;hey, college is the time when you experiment with drugs, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Ride</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/summer-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 08:51:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/summer-ride/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the good part of summer right now, the part where it&amp;rsquo;s warm and sunny and the days are long but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t gotten too humid out. I went on a nice bike ride yesterday morning along a route I used to take years ago when I first moved to Brooklyn that I haven&amp;rsquo;t done since. Truthfully I have not been riding my bike as much as I used to (and I used to ride it EVERYWHERE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Bird</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/early-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 07:01:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/early-bird/</guid>
      <description>I have been doing a Thing™ lately where I let the morning light wake me up instead of an alarm. Currently I am on an approximately two week streak of waking up at sunrise, and because the bedroom faces east, this means I have been waking up around 5:30 am. (Voluntarily!)
I wish I were one of those people who could function on 5 or 6 hours of sleep, but alas, somewhat embarrassingly I need a full 8 to 9 in order to really feel rested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brussels Sprouts</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/brussels-sprouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 08:09:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/brussels-sprouts/</guid>
      <description>As an adult I still sometimes have to trick myself into eating my vegetables. I made these roasted 고추장 (gochujang) honey Brussels sprouts yesterday that really did do the trick:
 고추장 (gochujang) honey Brussels sprouts
  Here&amp;rsquo;s my incredibly imprecise recipe.
고추장 (gochujang) honey Brussels sprouts  Brussels sprouts (you could probably do this with carrots also or any vegetable that is good for roasting) Honey (or any kind of sweet nectar—I used maple syrup this time) Lemon (or any kind of citrus/acid) Garlic powder Gochujang   Wash your sprouts, cut off the stems, and slice in half the long way (if the bulbous part is a head and the stem is a neck, cut it in a coronal or midline sagittal plane).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashback</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/flashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 06:51:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/flashback/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend I met up with a few of my former colleagues from residency for dinner and drinks. It felt a little bit like a meetup with high school friends might feel, if you spent high school removing gallbladders and incising and draining abscesses. (Maybe you did. I don&amp;rsquo;t know your life.)
Having a chance to confront and reflect on my former self in a controlled environment—in this case, a contemporary Mexican restaurant—was not a bad exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 07:40:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/tuesday/</guid>
      <description>The cadence of life is a little different now that I live in Brooklyn and work from home. In my 12 years in New York City, I have:
 lived in Brooklyn and worked in Brooklyn lived in Brooklyn and worked in Manhattan (the worst overall) lived in Manhattan and worked in Manhattan lived in Manhattan and worked from home lived in Brooklyn and worked from home  and the one that feels most like not working at all is living in Brooklyn and working from home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/now/</guid>
      <description>Just got back from two weeks of vacation, the longest consecutive time I&amp;rsquo;ve taken off fully (no email, no Slack) since 2016, when I took three months off after leaving residency.
Trying to embrace New York spring, which as usual can&amp;rsquo;t decide whether it wants to be beautiful and sunny or cold and gloomy (today is the latter).
Prepping for Asian American Pacific Islander Heritage Month events at work and socially, and reflecting on my own Korean American identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hon. Ketanji Brown Jackson&#39;s husband&#39;s socks</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/socks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 08:58:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/socks/</guid>
      <description>I keep an eye on the news through peripheral vision mostly but I noticed something about the confirmation hearings of the honorable Ketanji Brown Jackson that required my focus:
 Hon. Ketanji Brown Jackson&amp;rsquo;s husband
  No, not the husband. The SOCK:
 Hon. Ketanji Brown Jackson&amp;rsquo;s husband&amp;rsquo;s sock
  I&amp;rsquo;m not quite sure what the design is (looks like some kind of illustration of a face), but what I do know is that it is a funky sock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distracted</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/distracted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 09:30:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/distracted/</guid>
      <description>RIP to my attention span.
The world seems to be opening back up now that we are no longer surging (or are just between surges?), but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say that I feel normal again.
Lack of focus has been one of the most pronounced negative effects. For example, I sat down with a cup of coffee and opened up a text editor to write this note about an hour ago and have since abandoned the window no fewer than seven times (see Appendix).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 09:07:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/setup/</guid>
      <description>One of the top priorities when moving to Brooklyn was to have more space, particularly to have dedicated workspace. In our previous apartment, my office was a corner of the bedroom, which I was grateful to have, but also over time resentful. I love my work and my job (probably a litle too much), but seeing my workspace as the first thing upon waking and the last before sleep made it hard for my brain to rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Storycle (Bike Story)</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/bike-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 09:23:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/bike-story/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR I made a new page: kwon.nyc/bike
In January 2010 I was in my final year of medical school and had some rare free time for several weeks on a light rotation. My Local Bike Shop™ was offering classes on how to build a bike, so I enrolled and learned a lot about bike parts and bike maintenance. (Oddly enough, we didn&amp;rsquo;t actually build bikes.) Over the next few years I started building up a track bike, slowly amassing parts from my travels, getting the naked frame painted and framesaved, et cetera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Moves</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/power-moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 11:28:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/power-moves/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday one of my colleagues in a (virtual) meeting reportedly picked up a canister of coarse sea salt, announced &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just snacking,&amp;rdquo; and proceeded to eat the salt, which confused and maybe frightened the other meeting attendees.
It reminded me of the time I was rounding with my interns and medical students in the recovery room after scrubbing out of a long case and I was hungry so I pulled an apple out of my white coat pocket, ate most of it, noticed that there weren&amp;rsquo;t any trash cans close by, and so I ate the core and seeds as well and then deposited the stem in the breast pocket of my white coat to discard later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newyorkiversary</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 17:06:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</guid>
      <description>June 2021 marks my eleventh year in New York City. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be here this long. The Plan™ was never to stay in New York for this long. The Plan™ was to come here for five years to learn how to be a surgeon, then go back to Chicago and be a surgeon and live happily ever after.
When I was younger, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think that carefully about my future, which is kind of terrifying to think about now, how I made decisions about my life without really thinking about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colophon</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 18:07:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/colophon/</guid>
      <description>I use Hugo and DeployHQ to generate and deploy the site, respectively, and Github to host the source code. Locally, I use Byword to write and edit Markdown files, and Sublime Text to write and edit code.
The incredibly detailed illustration of my visage was done by my friend Leigh Peterson, who also taught me how to bathe a cat. (Those were two separate favors.)
I don&amp;rsquo;t really use design software to design websites, but I probably should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye and Hello</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/why-i-quit-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 22:02:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/why-i-quit-medicine/</guid>
      <description>As some of you have heard, I recently resigned from surgical residency, and am leaving clinical medicine.
Ten years ago, I decided to be a doctor. It was a decision that made perfect sense at the time: I wanted to help people who were suffering, and I was fortunate to have the ability and resources to gain entry into medical school. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure which specialty would be my calling, but shortly after starting my clinical rotations I fell in love with surgery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/transferrable-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/transferrable-skills/</guid>
      <description>Title: Transferrable skills Tags: Career changing
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a [blank], but I want to be a [&amp;lsquo;nother blank]&amp;rdquo;
 what are transferrable skills The patient with a tension pneumothorax who couldn&amp;rsquo;t breathe and had impending respiratory failure but refused to sign a consent form for me to place a life-saving chest tube? That&amp;rsquo;s getting buy-in from key stakeholders. The time I went to the diner across the street from the hospital to get a box of sugar to sprinkle on a prolapsed rectum in the ER to help reduce it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/contact/</guid>
      <description>Send me a message at rachel.kwon at gmail.com
Submit  --  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/links/</guid>
      <description>Internet friends and people I like:
 Daniel Bogan / Uses This in Melbourne Leigh Peterson in Hamilton, Ontario Chris Glass in Cincinnati Marianne in Connecticut Max in Brooklyn Eric Hu in Brooklyn Racquel in Brooklyn Rands in Los Gatos, CA Jung Yun (and Maybe) in Baltimore Sam Mok in Toronto Paul Graham in England  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
