<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kwon.nyc</title>
    <link>http://kwon.nyc/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kwon.nyc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 17:06:37 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kwon.nyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Newyorkiversary</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 17:06:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</guid>
      <description>June 2021 marks my eleventh year in New York City. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be here this long. The Plan™ was never to stay in New York for this long. The Plan™ was to come here for five years to learn how to be a surgeon, then go back to Chicago and be a surgeon and live happily ever after.
When I was younger, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think that carefully about my future, which is kind of terrifying to think about now, how I made decisions about my life without really thinking about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 18:07:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I&#39;m Rachel J. Kwon. I am a queer Korean American woman of average height in New York City. Like you, I am also a denizen of the internet. In 2016, I quit my job as a doctor (specifically, training to be a surgeon), which was one of the most important decisions of my life. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the topics I could talk about for 20 minutes without preparation, which they say is the sign of a thing you&amp;rsquo;re passionate about, or that you&amp;rsquo;re a rambler (I&amp;rsquo;m both 💅).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colophon</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 18:07:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/colophon/</guid>
      <description>I use Hugo and DeployHQ to generate and deploy the site, respectively, and Bitbucket to host the source code. Locally, I use Byword to write and edit Markdown files, and Sublime Text to write and edit code.
The incredibly detailed illustration of my visage was done by my friend Leigh Peterson, who also taught me how to bathe a cat. (Those were two separate favors.)
I don&amp;rsquo;t really use design software to design websites, but I probably should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye and Hello</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/notes/why-i-quit-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 22:02:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/notes/why-i-quit-medicine/</guid>
      <description>As some of you have heard, I recently resigned from surgical residency, and am leaving clinical medicine.
Ten years ago, I decided to be a doctor. It was a decision that made perfect sense at the time: I wanted to help people who were suffering, and I was fortunate to have the ability and resources to gain entry into medical school. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure which specialty would be my calling, but shortly after starting my clinical rotations I fell in love with surgery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/notes/transferrable-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/notes/transferrable-skills/</guid>
      <description>Title: Transferrable skills Tags: Career changing
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a [blank], but I want to be a [&amp;lsquo;nother blank]&amp;rdquo;
 what are transferrable skills The patient with a tension pneumothorax who couldn&amp;rsquo;t breathe and had impending respiratory failure but refused to sign a consent form for me to place a life-saving chest tube? That&amp;rsquo;s getting buy-in from key stakeholders. The time I went to the diner across the street from the hospital to get a box of sugar to sprinkle on a prolapsed rectum in the ER to help reduce it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/contact/</guid>
      <description>Send me a message at rachel.kwon at gmail.com
Submit  --  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/links/</guid>
      <description>Internet friends and people I like:
 Daniel Bogan / Uses This in Melbourne Leigh Peterson in Hamilton, Ontario Chris Glass in Cincinnati Marianne in Connecticut Max in Brooklyn Eric Hu in Brooklyn Racquel in Brooklyn Rands in Los Gatos, CA Jung Yun (and Maybe) in Baltimore Sam Mok in Toronto Paul Graham in England  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
