<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kwon.nyc</title>
    <link>http://kwon.nyc/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kwon.nyc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 16:46:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kwon.nyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Surgical Training Made Me a Better Product Leader</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/notes/hello-again-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 16:46:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/notes/hello-again-world/</guid>
      <description>Someone recently asked me if working in product (or more broadly, in business) was what I expected when I left surgery. The obvious answer was no &amp;ndash; building useful products for people is different from surgically operating on them (less blood loss, for one. Usually). But it&amp;rsquo;s funny how when two experiences are so vastly different, the similarities become that much more evident.
(It works the other way, too, when two things are so similar on first glance that the differences come into clearer focus the more you look at them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 18:07:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I&#39;m Rachel J. Kwon. I am a queer Korean American woman of average height in New York City. Like you, I am also a denizen of the internet. In 2016, I quit my job as a doctor (specifically, training to be a surgeon), which was one of the most important decisions of my life. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the topics I could talk about for 20 minutes without preparation, which they say is the sign of a thing you&amp;rsquo;re passionate about, or that you&amp;rsquo;re a rambler (I&amp;rsquo;m both 💅).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colophon</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 18:07:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/colophon/</guid>
      <description>I use Hugo and DeployHQ to generate and deploy the site, respectively, and Bitbucket to host the source code. Locally, I use Byword to write and edit Markdown files, and Sublime Text to write and edit code.
The incredibly detailed illustration of my visage was done by my friend Leigh Peterson, who also taught me how to bathe a cat. (Those were two separate favors.)
I don&amp;rsquo;t really use design software to design websites, but I probably should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye and Hello</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/notes/why-i-quit-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 22:02:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/notes/why-i-quit-medicine/</guid>
      <description>As some of you have heard, I recently resigned from surgical residency, and am leaving clinical medicine.
Ten years ago, I decided to be a doctor. It was a decision that made perfect sense at the time: I wanted to help people who were suffering, and I was fortunate to have the ability and resources to gain entry into medical school. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure which specialty would be my calling, but shortly after starting my clinical rotations I fell in love with surgery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/contact/</guid>
      <description>Send me a message at rachel.kwon at gmail.com
Submit  --  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/links/</guid>
      <description>Internet friends and people I like:
 Leigh Peterson Chris Glass Marianne Max Eric Hu Racquel Rands Jung Yun (and Maybe) Sam Mok Paul Graham  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
