<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on Kwon.nyc</title>
    <link>http://kwon.nyc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on Kwon.nyc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 08:46:45 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kwon.nyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Post-Med Life</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/notes/post-med-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 07:48:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/notes/post-med-life/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re pre-med before medical school, are you post-med after?
When you&amp;rsquo;re a baby, you pass major milestones every day or every week1. Then, every month or every year. As a working adult, life (and career) seems to happen in chunks of 3–5 years, ish.
When I was pre-med, I thought my life/career would look like this:
 College, 4 years Medical school, 4 years Residency, 5 years Fellowship, 1-3 years Surgeoning, forever, until I die ← post-med starts here  Instead, what happened was/is this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Moves</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/notes/power-moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 11:28:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/notes/power-moves/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday one of my colleagues in a (virtual) meeting reportedly picked up a canister of coarse sea salt, announced &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just snacking,&amp;rdquo; and proceeded to eat the salt, which confused and maybe frightened the other meeting attendees.
It reminded me of the time I was rounding with my interns and medical students in the recovery room after scrubbing out of a long case and I was hungry so I pulled an apple out of my white coat pocket, ate most of it, noticed that there weren&amp;rsquo;t any trash cans close by, and so I ate the core and seeds as well and then deposited the stem in the breast pocket of my white coat to discard later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newyorkiversary</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 17:06:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</guid>
      <description>June 2021 marks my eleventh year in New York City. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be here this long. The Plan™ was never to stay in New York for this long. The Plan™ was to come here for five years to learn how to be a surgeon, then go back to Chicago and be a surgeon and live happily ever after.
When I was younger, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think that carefully about my future, which is kind of terrifying to think about now, how I made decisions about my life without really thinking about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colophon</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 18:07:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/colophon/</guid>
      <description>I use Hugo and DeployHQ to generate and deploy the site, respectively, and Bitbucket to host the source code. Locally, I use Byword to write and edit Markdown files, and Sublime Text to write and edit code.
The incredibly detailed illustration of my visage was done by my friend Leigh Peterson, who also taught me how to bathe a cat. (Those were two separate favors.)
I don&amp;rsquo;t really use design software to design websites, but I probably should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye and Hello</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/notes/why-i-quit-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 22:02:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/notes/why-i-quit-medicine/</guid>
      <description>As some of you have heard, I recently resigned from surgical residency, and am leaving clinical medicine.
Ten years ago, I decided to be a doctor. It was a decision that made perfect sense at the time: I wanted to help people who were suffering, and I was fortunate to have the ability and resources to gain entry into medical school. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure which specialty would be my calling, but shortly after starting my clinical rotations I fell in love with surgery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/contact/</guid>
      <description>Send me a message at rachel.kwon at gmail.com
Submit  --  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>http://kwon.nyc/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kwon.nyc/links/</guid>
      <description>Internet friends and people I like:
 Leigh Peterson Chris Glass Marianne Max Eric Hu Racquel Rands Jung Yun (and Maybe) Sam Mok Paul Graham  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
